- 嘿  我上班去了   - 嘿  老爸
- Hey. See you later.  - Hey, dad.
在你走之前  我能问你件事吗
Before you go, can I ask you something?
- 哦  你还是问你妈妈去吧 - 为什么不能直接问你呢
- Oh, ask your mother.   - Why can't I ask you?
呃  因为不管我说什么
Well, because whatever answer I give you,
最后对的永远是你妈妈
She's gonna tell me it's the wrong one.
哇  老爸  你什么时候变得这么惧内了
Wow, dad. When did you become so afraid of mom?
这个  还是问你妈妈吧
I... ask your mother.
喂  老妈  能问你个问题吗
Hey, mom, can I ask you a question?
我服了  这年头让自己的汽车报警器别乱吵有那么难吗
Okay, why can't people learn to use their car alarms?
- 把那玩意关掉  混蛋  - 呃  妈  你貌似是在骂自己
- Turn it off, jerk!  - Uh, mom, that jerk is you.
- 啥  - 那是你自己的汽车上的报警器
- What?   - That's your car alarm.
哦  这样子啊  那就要另当别论了
Oh, well, that's entirely different.
- 怎么突然自己响起来了   -  那就是原因
- Why is it going off?   - That's why.
哦噢
Uh-oh.
小查莉正学着按按钮呢
Charlie's going through her button-pushing phase.
- 很可爱  对吧   - 对  对  确实很可爱
- Isn't it adorable?   - Yeah yeah, real cute baby.
- 闲话能就此打住么   - 对不起  儿子  你有什么事啊
- Can we get back to me now?  - Okay, honey, what is it?
学校的那群同学又拿我开涮了
The kids at school are teasing me again.
- 是因为你的头发吗   - 不  是因为我的自行车
- About your hair?   - No, about my bike.
- 我的头发怎么了   - 没什么
- What's wrong with my hair?   - Nothing.
你的发型从五岁开始就一直这样 挺合适的
It worked when you were five, it works now.
好了  说说你的自行车怎么了
Okay, now what about your bike?
那车太逊了  我要买辆新的
It's lame. I need a new one.
哦  你要辆新车  是吧
Oh, a new bike, huh?
- 要你爸跟你买去吧  - 真的
- Ask your father.   - Really?
不  我显然是在开玩笑
No, I'm just kidding.
我不会给你买新车的
You can't have a new bike.
大家都说一个人的车代表了这个人的地位
Everyone knows your bike is a statement of who you are.
而我的车则是在赤裸裸地告诉别人  车主是个傻瓜
My bike says "this guy is a total geek."
你的发型也是一样的
Same thing your haircut says.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
生活搞得一团糟
<i>Today's all burnt toast</i>
就要迟到  爸爸在叫
<i>Running late, and dad jokes</i>
我左脚的鞋子有没有人看到
<i>Has anybody seen my left shoe</i>
我闭上眼  咬口早餐
<i>I close my eyes, take a bite</i>
■
制作： fman1122  后期：  追忆似水年华  line
跳上车子  放声大笑
<i>Grab a ride, laugh out loud</i>
哎呀  老爸  鞋子就在房顶上
<i>There it is up on the roof</i>
我也曾这样生活  我已经顺利走过
<i>I've been there, I've survived</i>
所以听取我的建议
<i>So just take my advice</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby, </i>
世界有很多疯狂无奈
<i>Things are crazy</i>
可是我知道你会有美好未来
<i>But I know your future is bright</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby</i>
不要怀疑
<i>There is no maybe</i>
一切终会如你所愿
<i>Everything turns out all right</i>
生活有悲有喜
<i>Sure life is up and down</i>
但是请相信我  坚持就有好结果
<i>But trust me, it comes back around</i>
你会喜欢将来的你
<i>You're gonna love who you turn out to be</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby.</i>
查莉成长日记  第一季第二十三集
Good Luck Charlie  S01E23 Pushing Buttons
嘿  宝贝  忙什么呢
Hey, honey. What you working on?
哦  没什么
Oh, nothing.
回避一下不介意吧
Do you mind?
我禁不住要偷看一下  我瞥见你写了"妈妈"这个词
I can't help it. I saw the word "mom."
其实  我正在完成戏剧课上要的剧本
Okay, I'm writing a script for my drama class.
我们要拍一部小短片
We're supposed to shoot a short film.
关于我们生活中意义重大的时刻
About an important moment in our lives.
哇  哇  你写的是哪一个
Ooh ooh! Which moment?
我亲身参与过那么多瞬间
I've been involved in so many.
呃  我写的是那天你和爸爸告诉我
Well, it's about the day you and dad sat me down.
你们正在等待小查莉的降生
And told me you were expecting charlie.
- 能让我看看吗  - 好啊 等我写完了
- Can I read it?  - Sure, when I'm finished.
哦  别这样  这事太让我激动了
No, come on. I'm really excited.
- 让我粗略看几眼吧  - 好吧
- Give me a sneak peek.  - Okay.
啊  让我看看  鲍勃  啦啦啦
Okay, let's see here.  "Bob"... yak yak yak.
泰迪  啦啦啦  艾米
"Teddy"... blah blah blah. Amy
泰迪  我们有件事要告诉你
Teddy, we need to talk to you."
哇  这里写得太好了
Oh, this is really good.
妈妈  退场
Mom exits.
哪里写了  我没看到啊
Where does it say that? I don't see that.
不  不  不是写的  是我刚才说的
No no, it doesn't. I'm saying that.
伙计们  来见见俺的新女友  妮娜
Guys, I'd like you to meet my new girlfriend Nina.
妮娜  这是我最好的哥们 PJ
Nina, this is my best friend P.J....
- 嗨  - 这是她的姐姐 泰迪
- Hi.   - ...And his sister teddy.
- 很高兴认识你   - 哦  也很高兴认识你
- Nice to meet you.  - Oh, nice to meet you too.
进来吧  艾米特  你从哪捞了个女友来啊
Come on in. Emmett, when did you get a girlfriend?
大概20分钟之前  我速战速决把她搞定了
Like 20 minutes ago. I rushed right over as soon as it happened.
艾米特跟我讲了很多有关你的事
Emmett has told me so much about you.
她说话的口音很有特点
She talks like that all the time.
- 她是从南美来的  - 是委内瑞拉
- She's from south america.  - Venezuela.
你不是跟我说是南美吗
I thought you said south america.
艾米特  委内瑞拉就是南美的
Emmett, venezuela is in south america.
对吧
Right?
对  他们俩对地理什么的一窍不通
Yeah, they have trouble with subjects ending in "-ography."
还有数学  以及自然科学
And "-ath."  and "-ience."
泰迪  我能跟你单独聊会吗
Teddy, can I talk to you for a second?
- 行  - 我马上就回来
- Sure.  - I'll be right back.
哦
Okay.
那个  你来美国多长时间了
So how long have you been in the country?
- 只有一天  - 怪不得艾米特把你搞掂了
- Only one day. - That explains how you ended up with emmett.
那么  泰迪
So, Teddy,
俺现在既然是有女朋友的人了
Since I have a girlfriend now.
我们之间的那个什么
This thing that's been going on between us...
嗯  那段存在你幻想里头的东西
Mmm, that thing that exists only in your head?
对  就是那个   也该结束了
Yeah, that...  it's over.
好吧
Okay.
这样很好  把痛苦埋在内心
That's good. Deny the pain.
- 不要哭哟  - 没问题
- No tears?  - No problem.
- 真坚强   - 就这样吧  艾米特
- So brave.   - So... Emmett.
老爸  老爸  快过来啊
Dad! Dad, dad, quick! Get in here!
我的自行车不见了  被人给偷了
My bike is gone! Somebody stole it!
- 什么  - 看  车库的门现在打开着啊
- What? - Yeah, the garage door is wide open.
可我进屋前明明关了门的
But I closed it when I came in.
哎呀  肯定是被人撬开了
Well, somebody opened it,
而且我已经知道是谁干得了
And I think I know who.
- 小查莉干的   - 不是
- Charlie did it.  - No.
肯定是你  她绝对又在那里乱按按钮了
You did that! She's pushing the buttons again.
等一下  你先别吵  过来 小宝贝
Hang on, hang on.  Hey you.
小查莉怎么可能拿得到车库的遥控器啊
How did charlie even get the garage door remote?
我哪知道  我的威利不见了
Who cares? Wheelie is gone.
- 你管你的那辆车叫威利  -  曾经是
- You called your bike wheelie?  - I used to.
我爱那辆车
I loved that old bike.
好了好了  别难过了
Hey hey hey hey hey. It's okay.
这样吧  我给你买辆新的吧
You know what? We're gonna get you a new one.
行  我这就上车去
Okay, I'll be in the car.
宝贝女儿  你的剧本写得棒极了
Teddy honey, your script is terrific.
- 我很喜欢  - 哦  妈妈 您喜欢我真是太高兴了
- I love it.  - Oh, mom, I'm so glad you like it,
因为我还一直好担心你会到处挑刺呢
'Cause I thought you were gonna be critical.
可是你没有  你真是太棒了
But you're not critical, you're just really smart.
那么哪些人来演呢
Okay, so who's in it?
谁来演我们家的人
Who's playing the duncans?
哦  我们戏剧班上的同学
Oh, kids from my drama class.
一个叫沃特的  他来演我爸
This one kid, Walter, is playing dad.
随便了  那谁来演我
Blah blah blah. Who's playing me?
这个我还没有确定
I haven't cast the mom role yet.
我过一会要来进行那个角色的试镜
I'm having auditions later.
哦  好吧  这样吧  如果你需要我帮忙
Oh, okay. Well, if you need me to do anything,
尽管开口  我可以帮忙弄道具啊
Just let me know. I could do props,
服装啊  或者演妈妈这可角色啊  什么都行
Costumes or play mom... whatever.
又来了
Here we go.
对了  我记得有没有跟你说过
You know, I don't know if I've told you this,
我在年轻的时候曾经演过很多的戏剧
But when I was younger I did a lot of theater.
真的吗  丹佛西南社区学院的
Really? What did the southwest denver.
《每日号角》怎么评价的
Community college "daily bugle" say?
它们说我在"热铁皮屋顶上的猫 "里面
The southwest denver community college "daily bugle"
注：1958电影 又名朱门巧妇
演的玛姬实在是
Called my maggie from "cat on a hot tin roof"
美喵无比
Purr-fect.
这个嘛  妈  我还是准备找跟我一起上戏剧课的同学
Ah. Look, mom. I'm supposed to use kids.
来演短片里面的角色
From my drama class in the video.
当然  你当然应该这样
Of course. Of course you are.
- 我完全理解  - 谢谢
- I understand.  - Thanks.
你知道我现在什么感觉吗
You know what I feel like?
我感觉自己就像热铁皮屋顶上的那只猫
I feel all the time like a cat on a hot tin roof.
爸  妈又在骚扰我
Dad! Mom's bugging me!
- 你好  - 哦 嗨
- Hello there.  - Oh, hi.
- 你是PJ对吧   - 没错
- It's P.J., right?  - That's right.
那个  你觉得这所高中怎么样
So how are you liking south high?
哦  大家都对我很好
Oh, everyone is so nice.
有的人对我特别好
Some more nice than others.
这样  很好啊
That's... Nice.
呃  我希望你不要认为我太突兀
Uh, I hope you don't think I'm being too forward,
我觉得你魅力十足
But I find you very intriguing.
我觉得你现在离我貌似太近了
I find you standing very close now.
这是我的手机号码  有空打给我哟
This is my number. I hope you'll use it.
你不是有男朋友了吗
Don't you already have a boyfriend?
没啊  不过我正希望有  再见
No, but I'm hoping to. Ciao.
什么意思
Ciao?
哦  不会吧  她都开始跟我起小名了
Oh, no, she already has a nickname for me.
- 嗨 亲爱的  - 嘿
- Hi, honey.  - Hey.
车库里怎么突然冒出辆新自行车
Why is there a new bike in the garage?
盖比的自行车被偷了  可怜的孩子  他怪伤心的
Gabe's bike got stolen. Poor kid was crushed.
你没搞错吧  他一直巴不得甩掉那辆旧自行车
What are you talking about? He hated his old bike.
- 是威利吗   - 没错  他特别想甩掉
- Wheelie?  - Yes, weally.
注：老妈把Wheelie当成Really了
我们说这个有意义吗
Are we talking like this for a weason?
不  威利是他自行车的名字
No, wheelie is what he called his bike.
昨天他还管那辆自行车叫废铁
Yesterday he called his bike lame.
然后求我给他买辆新的
And then asked me for a new one.
这样啊
Huh.
有点可疑  你说呢
Kinda suspicious, don't you think?
没错
Yeah.
确实很可疑
It weally is.
嘿  你知不知道香蕉在委内瑞拉那儿怎么说
Hey, do you know how they say bananas in venezuela?
就叫"香 蕉"
Bananas.
你知不知道委内瑞拉那儿的女孩怎么称呼
Do you know what girls from venezuela call the guy.
她们想偷偷约会的男生吗  而且是"朋友妻不客气那种"
They secretly want to date behind their best friend's back?
巧儿
Ciao.
等一下  你说啥
Wait. What?
妮娜今天在学校主动跟我调情
Nina flirted with me at school today.
- 怎么可能   - 绝对是
- No, she didn't.  - Did too.
好吧  八成是你没听懂她说的什么吧
Okay, maybe you didn't understand her.
我至少听得懂英语
I understand <i>english.</i>
我从七岁起就会说英语了
I've been speaking it since I was seven.
我觉得是你想太多了吧
I think you're making things up.
伙计  她跟我说"我觉得你魅力十足"
Dude, she said " I find you intriguing."
我虽然不会说西班牙语  但那句话肯定是在挑逗我
Now I don't speak spanish, but that has got to be a come-on.
好啦  你们俩准备好了不
All righty. Are you guys ready?
嘿  我想你的同学们可能需要些提神的东西
Hey. I thought you kids might like some refreshments.
谢谢你 宝贝 有你为伴我真幸运
Thank you, honey. I'm so lucky to have you.
呃  妈妈  这就是沃特  她来演剧中的爸爸
Uh, mom, that's walter. He's playing dad.
请称呼我  鲍勃
Please, call me Bob.
这能让我更快融入角色
It'll help me stay in character.
把你的手拿开  鲍勃
Take your arm away, bob.
这是凯米  她来演剧中的我
And this is Kimmy. She's playing me.
有个关于我的角色有个问题要问你
Question about character.
为什么叫她泰迪
Why did you name her teddy?
呃  我们夫妻俩挺喜欢那名字
Well, we just really liked the name.
这个答案真是把我要雷翻了
That was you blowing my mind.
全班只有她试演这个角色
She was the only one who tried out.
哦  那你找到人来演剧中的我了吗
Well, have you found a mom yet?
这个嘛  还没有  那些候选人还在门口等着呢
Oh, no, all the amy candidates are out on the porch.
好吧  随便了
Oh, okay. Whatever.
我都没指望这事儿  真的
I wasn't even thinking about that, really.
是不是有邮件来了  我这就出去看看
Is that the mail I hear? I'm just gonna go check and find out.
很抱歉  女孩们 试镜取消了
Sorry, girls, the video sheet's been canceled.
其实呢  我们邓肯家的人头上都容易长虱子
Yeah, the duncans have head lice.
好了  第一个
Okay, first let's...
咦  人怎么都没影了呢
Hey, where'd everybody go?
我怎么会知道
Beats me.
有什么老妈我可以帮忙的呢
Anything mom can do for you?
哇  您真是太强大了
Wow. You're unbelievable. Okay, well,
好吧  都到这份儿上了  您愿不愿意
Seeing as I have no other choice, would you...
没问题
Yes!
好吧  就这么样吧
Okay, here we.
妈  快点  我马上要开始了
Mom, come on. I want to get started.
- 来了  - 我花在等那女人上的时间
- Coming!   - I spend more time.
比我排练的时间还要多
Waiting for that woman.
妈  你怎么换衣服了
Mom, why did you change?
- 按剧本上写的你应该穿便装啊   - 哦  乖女儿
- The script says Amy's in scrubs.   - Oh, honey,
我在大学的演出生涯里学到了一件事
I learned in college theater.
剧本永远只不过是个参考
That the script is really just an outline.
好吧  那么各位  我们准备开始了
Okay. All right, everyone, here we go.
鲍勃还有艾米  你们坐在沙发上
Bob and Amy, you're on the couch.
泰迪从那里进入  还有  记住各位
Teddy enters from over there. Now remember, guys,
这个仅仅是排练  所以还是按照剧本上的来
This is just a rehearsal so use your scripts.
开拍
And action.
泰迪  你能过来一会吗
"Teddy, can you come here a minute?"
泰迪紧张地走向沙发
"Teddy crosses to the couch, nervous.
我有麻烦了吗  问号
'Am I in trouble'... question mark."
不对  不对  凯米 只用读台词
No no no, kimmy, just the lines, honey.
别的东西不用读  懂了吗
Not the other stuff, okay?
开拍
And action.
泰迪  我们有事要跟你说
"Teddy, we need to talk to you."
我有麻烦了吗
"Am I in trouble?"
好吧  我就直接说了吧
"Well, I'll just say it.
- 你妈妈要生个小宝宝了  - 等一下  等一下
- Your mother's gonna have a baby."   - Okay, can we stop?
能先停一下吗  我很抱歉
Can we stop? I'm sorry.
那些话  我感觉不符合我说话的风格
These words... they just don't fit into my mouth comfortably.
可你当时就是这么说的啊
But it's what happened. It's exactly what you said.
那天你还穿着便服呢
The day you were supposed to be wearing scrubs.
好吧  你说得很对  但是你是想完全按照事实死板地拍呢
Okay, valid point, but do we want to make it real.
还是想把故事拍得更精彩一些呢
Or do we want to make it good?
我只是想在电池耗完之前把它给拍完
I want to make it before my battery dies.
啊  很不错  这辆新车确实很酷啊
Yeah. Well, that new bike sure is a beauty.
那还用说  老爸
Sure is, dad.
- 好了  你好好玩吧   - 嗯
- All right. Have fun. - Okay.
- 儿子  在你走之前  - 怎么了
- Gabe, before you go... - Yeah?
- 问你一件事   - 说吧
- ...One quick question.   - Mm-hmm.
你还记得小查莉手上拿着的那个遥控器吧
You know that garage door remote that charlie had?
- 记得啊  - 你觉得她是怎么从壁橱上拿到那玩意的
- Mm-hmm. - How do you think she got that down from the cupboard?
- 这问题你还是得问她吧  - 说得也是
- Maybe you should ask charlie.  - Yeah, well,
你明明知道我没法那么做
You know I can't do that.
哦  对了  她还不会说话  对吧
Oh, because she can't talk yet.
- 没错  - 哎  真是太可惜了
- Yeah.   - Yeah, that is a bummer.
对  没错
Yeah, it sure is.
好吧  就这样吧  你玩去吧
All right. You know what? I'll see you later.
好
Okay.
等一下  还有件事
You know what? Just one more thing.
说吧
Mm-hmm.
你知道吗  我觉得
You know, I don't even think.
遥控器不能在厨房控制车库的开关
That remote works from the kitchen where charlie was.
老爸  你到底想说什么啊
Dad, what are you trying to say?
你不会是在怀疑我吧
Are you accusing me of something?
没  我只是想问问你啥时候回来
No, I just wanna know when you're gonna be back.
哦  半个小时吧  我现在能出去了吗
Oh, half an hour. Can I go now?
当然  儿子
Of course you can, gabe.
你想啥时候去玩就可以啥时候去玩
You've always been free to go.
好吧
Okay.
看  看  她就在那
Okay okay, there she is.
我现在就过去证明给你看  她喜欢的是我
Now I'm going to prove to you that she likes me.
- 而不是你  - 行  行
- And not you.  - Okay. Okay.
- 嗨   - 嗨
- Hi.   - Hi.
- 你好  - 你好
- Hi.    - Hi.
到目前为止我们是平手
So far it's a tie.
瞧  俺们哥俩在学校都是万人迷
Okay, I know we both have a lot to offer,
但你还是得从俺们中间选一个
But you're gonna have to choose between us.
哦  我选PJ
Oh, I choose P.J.
好吧  重来一次
Okay, let's try that again.
不过友情提示一下  你有两个选项可以选择哟
And remember it's a multiple-choice question.
我还是选PJ
My choice is still P.J.
对不起  我不能跟你约会
I'm sorry, I can't go out with you.
我不能那样对艾米特  兄弟是手足  女人是衣服
I wouldn't do that to emmett. Pals before gals.
- 谢了  兄弟  - 你也不会见色忘义的对吧
- Thanks, man. - You'd do the same for me, right?
当然  你可以这么想
Yeah, let's go with that.
等一下  我知道是怎么回事了
Wait a minute. I know what's going on here.
- 你们把我当成妮娜了  - 难道你不是吗
- You think I'm nina.  - You're not?
不是  我是蒂娜  那才是妮娜
No! I'm tina. That's nina.
原来是双胞胎啊
Twins!
等下  我们还等什么啊
Wait. What are we doing?
然后我就说
And then I could say,
乖女儿  妈妈马上又要有个小宝宝了
"Teddy girl, mama's having a baby child!"
怎么样  怎么样 这样一来是不是好多了
Right? Right? Isn't that better?
这样不是更自然吗
Doesn't it make more sense.
艾米告诉泰迪关于小宝宝的事
That Amy would tell Teddy about the baby?
妈妈马上又要有个小宝宝了
"Mama's having a baby child"?
女儿啊  我只是想让当时的情感
Well, teddy, I'm just trying to find.
真实地再现
The emotional truth to the piece.
这个嘛  还是不必了吧
No thank you.
好吧  你想让我照着剧本读  那我就当个机器人好了
Okay, fine. You want me to be a robot, I'll be a robot.
我演机器人
I'll be a robot.
我-又-有-麻-烦-了-吗
Am I in trouble?
不  不  不
No. No no no no no.
不要像机器人似的  我们就照着剧本来就行了
Nobody's a robot. We're doing the script as written.
好了  各就各位
Okay, places everyone.
开拍
And action.
女儿啊  你能过来一下吗
Teddy, can you come here a minute?
我又有麻烦了
Am I in trouble?
我们有件事要跟你说
Teddy, we need to talk to you.
好吧  我就直接说了
Well, I'll just say it...
你妈妈马上又要有个小宝宝了
Your mother's gonna have a baby.
什么
A what?
小宝宝  你马上又要有个
A baby. You're gonna have.
弟弟或者妹妹了
A new little brother or sister.
- 啊  - 你这是在干什么
- Oh! - Now what are you doing?
刚才小宝宝在踢我的肚子
I just felt the baby kick.
不  不  不
No. No no no.
这不可能  那个时候小宝宝脚还没有长出来
That's impossible. The baby doesn't have feet yet.
好吧  我只是在试着
Okay. You know what? I'm just trying.
寻找我当时的内心情感
To figure out the mix of emotions that I was feeling that day.
兴奋啊  困惑啊
You know, the excitement, the confusion,
害怕啊  过度亢奋啊
The fear, the hormones.
行  行  你知道我当时是什么感受吗
Yeah, do you know what I was feeling that day?
我当时在想  你怎么又要生下一个小孩
It was "why are you having another baby?
你甚至连已经有的这三个孩子都照顾不过来
You barely have time for the three kids you have now."
那句是剧本里的吗  我有点晕了
Was that in the script? Because I'm lost.
宝贝
Teddy honey,
你怎么了
What was that?
对不起  妈妈  我刚才不该那么对你说话
I'm sorry, mom. I shouldn't have said that.
你真的是那么想的吗
Well, is that really how you felt?
我们又有了一个孩子真的让你很生气吗
Were you really mad that we were having another baby?
- 嗯  我想有点吧  - 你为什么不直接跟我说呢
- Yeah, I kinda was.  - Why didn't you say something?
妈  我又能说什么呢
Mom, what was I supposed to say?
你已经怀上小查莉了  而且你好激动
Charlie was on the way. You were all so excited.
激动  我当时真不知道之后的日子该怎么办
Excited? I didn't know how we were gonna make it all work.
- 我当时好害怕  - 真的  可你当时一点没显得害怕啊
- I was terrified. - Really? 'Cause you didn't show it.
那是因为我是个一流的演员
That's because I'm a really great actress.
过来  坐下
Come here. Sit down.
你现在还是那样觉得吗
Do you still feel that way,
感觉我和你爸爸没有花足够时间来关心你
Like we don't have enough time for you?
说心里话  我觉得
Actually, today I thought maybe you had.
今天你陪我的时间有点太多了
A little bit too much time for me.
好了  说真的
No. Seriously,
我不知道你和爸爸是怎么样应对这些的
I don't know how you're doing it,
但是你们俩做得确实很出色
But you guys are doing a great job.
那是因为我们俩并不是独自撑起这个家
Well, that's because we're not doing it alone,
你也帮我们分担了许多
And one of the big reasons it works is you.
男生们也做了挺多的
The boys help out too.
不过你确实说的是实话  主要靠的还是我啦
But you're right, it's mostly me.
听我说  女儿
Look, teddy. In the future,
无论你以后遇到什么不愉快  都告诉我  好吗
If ever you're feeling something, you've got to tell me, okay?
过来  抱一个
Come here. Come here.
我希望我们母女俩之间能坦诚相见
I want us to always be honest with each other.
好  我以后再也不瞒你了
Okay, I'll be honest with you.
按台词写的来演  否则我就要换人啦
Say the lines as written or you're fired.
啊
Aww.
怎么了  儿子
What's the matter, gabe?
- 哦  是老爸你啊 - 你还好吧
- Um, dad...   - Are you okay?
怎么像是被吓着了
You look shook up.
- 我的威利回来了  - 我知道  很棒  不是么
- Wheelie's back.  - I know! Isn't it great?
是啊  那个
Yay. Um...
你怎么把它找回来的啊
How did you find him?
哦  我下班回家的路上
Oh, I came home from work,
看见那个叫杰克的小子骑着你的车
I saw that kid Jake on your bike,
然后我就报了警  把他抓住了
So I called the cops and they arrested him.
他们把杰克抓了
They arrested Jake?
可他还未成年啊
But he's just a kid.
哦  等他放出来也就该成年了
Ooh, he won't be when he gets out.
- 什么  - 怎么了  儿子
- What?   - What's wrong, son?
有什么让你难过的吗
Something bothering you?
呃  没有啊
Um... No.
没有  不过  倒是有些事让我很困惑啊
No? Well, something's bothering me,
因为我猜想事情的真相应该是这样子的吧
Because here's what I think really happened.
首先  你把自行车卖给了杰克
First, you sold your bike to Jake
并且把钱收好
And then you pocketed the money.
然后  你用车库外面的控制板
Then you opened the garage door...
打开了车库大门
...Using the keypad.
最后  你从厨房里的壁橱
Finally, you grabbed the remote
拿出了遥控器
From the kitchen cabinet
把它塞到了小查莉的手上
And you planted it on charlie.
很生动的推理  可是您没证据啊
Interesting theory, but it doesn't prove a thing.
没错  你说得对
You're right. You're right.
我确实没有铁证
I didn't have any hard proof,
但是我想了又想  想了又想
But I kept thinking, thinking.
想了又想
And thinking.
然后门铃响了
And then a bell went off.
- 盖比在家吗  - 不在
- Is gabe here?   - No.
告诉他一个叫杰克的要他退回我的10块钱
Tell him Jake wants his $10 back.
这辆破车就是一堆废铁
This bike is a piece of junk.
到此  一切真相大白
And that's when all the pieces fell into place.
好吧  被你发现了
All right, you got me.
你准备怎么办
Now what happens?
还是问你妈妈去吧
Ask your mother.
我们从自行车店回来了
Back from the bike store.
小查莉  你哥哥有话要对你说
Charlie, your brother has something he would like to say to you.
去吧  儿子
Go ahead, gabe.
查莉  我不该陷害你的
Charlie, I'm sorry I tried to frame you.
哦  还记不记得那回我对你也是这么说的
Aw. Remember the first time I said that to you?
就像昨天一样历历在目
Like it was yesterday.
你哥哥还给你准备了一件礼物来作为补偿
And now here is a little I'm-sorry present from your brother.
好了  拿进来吧
Okay, bring it in.
- 哇   -  好棒
- Oh.  - Yay!
高兴吧  我们拿盖比的新自行车换了这辆车
Yeah, we exchanged gabe's new bike for this one.
- 谢谢   - 不用谢啦
- Thank you.  - You're welcome.
小查莉  这可是你的第一辆自行车哟
Charlie, there you are on your very first bike.
对啊  对啊  泰迪啊
Yeah yeah. Teddy girl,
妈妈的小宝宝有了辆新的自行车
Mama's baby child has a new tricycle!
粉红色的  而且还有张可爱的小贴纸哟
It's pink and red and it's got little stickers on it.
没错  老妈又成功地抢了你第一次骑车的镜头
Yup, and there's mom stealing your very first spotlight.
祝你好运啰  小查莉
Good luck, charlie.
我好内疚  我居然分不清谁是我爸
I feel so bad. I just can't tell them apart.
- 确实挺难的  - 而我又不想直接上前去问他们
- It is hard.  - And I don't want to offend them.
其实  我们只用找到一个小小的区别就行了
Well, you just have to find one little thing that's different.
你发现了什么吗
What do you think?
我分不清啊  亏我还嫁给了其中一个
I have no idea, and I'm married to one of them.
嘿  呃  老爸们
Hey, uh, dads,
能给我五块钱吗
Can I have five bucks?
嘿嘿  有两个爹真是太爽了
Huh. I love having two dads.
难以置信  我觉得我们是分不出来了
Unbelievable! We'll never figure it out!
等一下  等一下
Wait. Wait.
这就对了  那绝对是我的老公
Yup. That's my guy.